<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>ᓚᘏᗢ on Algorithms and Sequences</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/shashankpritam/shashankpritam.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ᓚᘏᗢ on Algorithms and Sequences</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.128.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/shashankpritam/shashankpritam.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Simplicity, Efficiency, and the Art of Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shashankpritam/shashankpritam.github.io/blog/simplicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shashankpritam/shashankpritam.github.io/blog/simplicity/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Demystifying Complexity: Finding Clarity in Simplicity In our information-saturated age, complexity often impedes progress. An overabundance of information can lead to:
Information Overload Our brains can only process so much information. Too many details overwhelm our ability to understand and solve problems. Decision Fatigue Weighing lots of complex options tires out our decision-making. The more choices we face, the worse our decisions get. Analysis Paralysis With tons of data, we become unable to choose.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The issue of distractions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shashankpritam/shashankpritam.github.io/blog/distractions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shashankpritam/shashankpritam.github.io/blog/distractions/</guid>
      <description>Distractions are things that pull our attention away from what we&amp;rsquo;re doing. It can be something as familiar as the buzz of a smartphone or a sudden thought about something we have to do later. Nowadays, many distractions come from technology like social media, emails, or shows and movies on entertainment platforms. Memes and short video forms have become new sources of entertainment. These distractions can mess with our ability to get things done, making us take longer to finish tasks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shashankpritam/shashankpritam.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shashankpritam/shashankpritam.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s On The Blog? What I hope to post in future?
A mix of whatever&amp;rsquo;s been capturing my interest lately in reading and learning Do you have any questions, or just want to chat about science, tech, or anything else? Feel free to send me an email (firstname.lastname@icloud.com)! Or schedule a meeting with me here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Current Readings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shashankpritam/shashankpritam.github.io/readings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shashankpritam/shashankpritam.github.io/readings/</guid>
      <description>Bookshelf Here are some of books that I am currently reading:
&amp;ldquo;A Biologist&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Mathematical Modeling in Ecology and Evolution&amp;rdquo; by Sarah P. Otto and Troy Day &amp;ldquo;Modeling Life: The Mathematics of Biological Systems&amp;rdquo; by Alan Garfinkel, Jane Shevtsov, and Yina Guo &amp;ldquo;The Rust Programming Language&amp;rdquo; by Steve Klabnik and Carol Nichols, with contributions from the Rust Community &amp;ldquo;Rust for Rustaceans : Idiomatic Programming for Experienced Developers&amp;rdquo; by Jon Gjengset Cool Websites A few useful and interesting websites:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shashankpritam/shashankpritam.github.io/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shashankpritam/shashankpritam.github.io/cv/</guid>
      <description>My Curriculum Vitae</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shashankpritam/shashankpritam.github.io/pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shashankpritam/shashankpritam.github.io/pictures/</guid>
      <description>Pictures!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statement of Teaching Philosophy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/shashankpritam/shashankpritam.github.io/teaching-philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/shashankpritam/shashankpritam.github.io/teaching-philosophy/</guid>
      <description>As an educator, my teaching philosophy is centered around fostering a balanced power dynamic in the classroom that encourages productivity, nurtures mental health, and promotes an inclusive and welcoming environment. Mental health is as important as physical health; education should never compromise either aspect. My approach to teaching emphasizes genuine curiosity, accessibility, and guiding students toward valuable resources when necessary.
Prioritizing mental health and well-being A student’s mental health is paramount; my teaching practices reflect this commitment.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
