<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Intersecting Genetics and Computation on GoModelBio</title>
    <link>https://www.gomodelbio.systems/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Intersecting Genetics and Computation on GoModelBio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gomodelbio.systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Distractions</title>
      <link>https://www.gomodelbio.systems/blog/post1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gomodelbio.systems/blog/post1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Understanding Distractions Discuss what distractions are and how they impact our productivity and well-being. Talk about the most common sources of distraction in our modern world (like smartphones and social media).
The FOMO Phenomenon Explain the concept of FOMO and its implications. Discuss why we experience it and how it contributes to distraction and stress.
The Cost of FOMO Discuss the effects of FOMO on our mental health, relationships, productivity, and overall quality of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.gomodelbio.systems/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gomodelbio.systems/about/</guid>
      <description>Welcome! Hello, and thank you for visiting my webpage! I am a passionate doctoral student specializing in Biological Sciences with a particular fascination for Population Genetics. The world of genetics, with its intricate complexities and profound implications, is the driving force behind my studies and research.
I created this webpage as a platform to share my journey and explore topics that pique my curiosity in the field of genetics. Here, I will delve into and explain complex concepts such as genetic algorithms, bioinformatics, DNA sequencing, genomics, and proteomics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current Readings</title>
      <link>https://www.gomodelbio.systems/readings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gomodelbio.systems/readings/</guid>
      <description>Articles The following are some current articles that have caught my interest:
&amp;ldquo;Ten Things You Should Know about Transposable Elements&amp;rdquo; by Guillaume Bourque, et al., in Genome Biology, vol. 19, no. 1, Nov. 2018, p. 199. Read Article
&amp;ldquo;History of the Discovery of a Master Locus Producing PiRNAs: The Flamenco/COM Locus in Drosophila Melanogaster&amp;rdquo; by Goriaux Coline, et al., in Frontiers in Genetics, vol. 5, Aug. 2014, p. 257. Read Article</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>https://www.gomodelbio.systems/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gomodelbio.systems/cv/</guid>
      <description>My Curriculum Vitae</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pictures</title>
      <link>https://www.gomodelbio.systems/pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gomodelbio.systems/pictures/</guid>
      <description>Pictures!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement of Teaching Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://www.gomodelbio.systems/teaching-philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gomodelbio.systems/teaching-philosophy/</guid>
      <description>As an educator, my teaching philosophy is centered around fostering a balanced power dynamic in the classroom that encourages productivity, nurtures mental health, and promotes an inclusive and welcoming environment. Mental health is as important as physical health; education should never compromise either aspect. My approach to teaching emphasizes genuine curiosity, accessibility, and guiding students toward valuable resources when necessary.
Prioritizing mental health and well-being A student’s mental health is paramount; my teaching practices reflect this commitment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
